Guide to the Ambassador Auditorium Collection ARS.0043
Archive of Recorded Sound
- Series 10: Concert Recordings, 252 boxes (266.2 linear ft.)
  - Video Tapes
    - Video Cassettes (VHS): Performances, Promotional, Interviews/Awards, and Miscellaneous:, 1987 -- 1994; 29 video cassettes (Box 75)
      Henderson, Joe; Cheatham, Jeannie; Cheatham, Jimmy; Sweet Baby Blues Band; Shaw, Marlena; Smith, Jimmy; Klugh, Earl; Domingo, Plácido; Wanamaker, Sam; Mitchell, Arthur; Dance Theatre of Harlem; Ivo Pogorelich International Solo Piano Competition; Crawford, Hank; Price, Leontyne; Pogorelich, Ivo
    - Video Tapes: Performances and Promotional:, 1974 -- 1993; 7 open reel tapes (1" tape on 9 or 10 1/2" reel) (Box 76)
      08-08-1993: Pasadena Jazz Festival footage
      04-24-1987: Vienna Symphony in concert, directed by [Carlo Maria] Giulini 07-22-1974
      05-23-1982: [2 video tapes] Vladimir Horowitz, Command Performance in London, Reels 1 and 2
      08-05-1980: Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra (L.A.C.O.)
      08-22-1980: Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra (L.A.C.O.)
      07-22-1982: AICF 1982 Promos
      Horowitz, Vladimir; Wiener Symphoniker; Giulini, Carlo Maria; Pasadena Jazz Festival; Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra
    - Video Tapes: Performances and Promotional:, 1982 -- 1994; 7 open reel tapes (1" tape on 9" or 10 1/2" reel) (Box 77)
      04-09-1982; 12-16-1982; 03-30-1983: AICF Promos: Dance Theatre of Harlem; Ballet Folclorico Eng./Spanish
      06-02-1994 [6 video tapes]: Mel Tormé Second Half; [tapes are labeled separately:] Cam 1, Cam 2, Original Cam 2 Reel 2, Cam 3, Cam 5, SWITCHED
      Tormé, Mel; Dance Theatre of Harlem
    - Video Tapes: Pasadena Jazz Festival:, 08-06-1994; 7 open reel tapes (1" tape on 10 1/2" reel) (Box 78)
      08-06-1994: [7 video tapes] Pasadena Jazz Festival, Jeannie & Jimmy Cheatham; [tapes are labeled separately:] SWITCHED, Cam 1, Cam 2, Cam 3, Cam 4, Cam 5, Cam 6
      Pasadena Jazz Festival; Cheatham, Jeannie; Cheatham, Jimmy
    - Video Tapes: Pasadena Jazz Festival:, 08-06-1994; 7 open reel tapes (1" tape on 10 1/2" reel) (Box 79)
      08-06-1994: [7 video tapes] Pasadena Jazz Festival, Jimmy Smith Quartet; [tapes are labeled separately:] SWITCHED, Cam 1, Cam 2, Cam 3, Cam 4, Cam 5, Cam 6
      Pasadena Jazz Festival; Smith, Jimmy
    - Video Tapes: Pasadena Jazz Festival:, 08-07-1994; 7 open reel tapes (1" tape on 10 1/2" reel) (Box 80)
      08-07-1994: [7 video tapes] Pasadena Jazz Festival, Earl Klugh
      Klugh, Earl; Pasadena Jazz Festival
    - Video Tapes: Pasadena Jazz Festival:, 08-07-1994; 7 open reel tapes (1" tape on 10 1/2" reel) (Box 81)
      08-07-1994: [7 video tapes] Pasadena Jazz Festival, Benny Green Trio; [tapes are labeled separately:] SWITCHED, Cam 1, Cam 2, Cam 3, Cam 4, Cam 5, Cam 6
      Benny Green Trio; Green, Benny; Pasadena Jazz Festival
    - Video Tapes: Pasadena Jazz Festival:, 08-07-1994; 7 open reel tapes (1" tape on 10 1/2" reel) (Box 82)
      08-07-1994: [7 video tapes] Pasadena Jazz Festival, Joe Henderson Trio; [tapes are labeled separately:] SWITCHED, Cam 1, Cam 2, Cam 3, Cam 4, Cam 5, Cam 6
      Pasadena Jazz Festival; Henderson, Joe
    - Video Tapes: Performances:, 07-11-1994 -- 06-21-1995; 7 open reel tapes (1" tape on 10 1/2" reel) (Box 83)
      07-11-1994: [Ken Peplowski footage]
      08-23-1994: Mel Tormé (long version)
      03-17-1995: Jimmy Smith [Pasadena Jazz Festival]
      06-07-1995: Joe Henderson [Pasadena Jazz Festival]
      06-19-1995: Earl Klugh [Pasadena Jazz Festival]
      06-20-1995: Jimmy Smith [Pasadena Jazz Festival]
      06-21-1995: Joe Henderson [Pasadena Jazz Festival]
      Pasadena Jazz Festival; Tormé, Mel; Smith, Jimmy; Klugh, Earl; Henderson, Joe
    - Video Tapes: Performances:, 1974 -- 1995; 4 open reel tapes (2" tape on 12 1/2" reel; 1" tape on 11 1/2" reel) (Box 84)
      12-29-1974: Vienna Symphony Special
      03-29-1995: Benny Green [1994 Pasadena Jazz Festival]
      06-21-1995: Benny Green [1994 Pasadena Jazz Festival]
      [1974]: "Emperor" Waltz J. Strauss; C.M. Giulini & Vienna Symphony
      Giulini, Carlo Maria; Wiener Symphoniker; Benny Green Trio; Pasadena Jazz Festival; Green, Benny
    - Video Tapes: Performances:, 1974 -- 1993; 4 open reel tapes (2" tape on 12 1/2" reel; 1" tape on 10 1/2" reel) (Box 85)
      12-16-1974 [1975?]: [Artur] Rubinstein 2nd Half
      02-18-1975 [from label: Edited 02-28-1975; Cleaned 05-19-1983]: [Artur] Rubinstein Encores & Presentation
      02-28-1975: [Artur] Rubinstein Encores & Presentation
      08-08-1993: Pasadena Jazz Festival Reel 2
      Rubinstein, Artur; Pasadena Jazz Festival
    - Video Tapes: Performances:, 1974 -- 1975; 3 open reel tapes (2" tape on 12 1/2" reel) (Box 86)
      12-16-1974 [1975?]: [from note on reel] Artur Rubinstein, second half
      [1975?]: [Artur] Rubinstein Worktape
      [1975?]: [Artur] Rubinstein 1st Half
      Rubinstein, Artur
    - Video Tapes: Performances:, 1974 -- 1975; 4 open reel tapes (2" tape on 12 1/2" reel; 2" tape on 14" reel) (Box 87)
      [1974]: Stravinsky Firebird Final Edited Copy [from the inaugural concerts that took place April 7, 8, and 9, 1974, featuring the Vienna Symphony Orchestra and conductor Carlo Maria Giulini. The complete program was as follows: Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Egmont. Ouverture -- Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Zhar-ptit︠s︡a. Suite (1919) -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Symphonies, no. 1, op. 68, C minor]
      01-15-1975: [3 tapes] [Artur] Rubinstein
      Rubinstein, Artur; Giulini, Carlo Maria; Wiener Symphoniker
    - Video Tapes: Performances:, 1974; 4 open reel tapes (2" tape on 12 1/2" reel) (Box 88)
      Video tape reels are identified by date and other information taken from the container, the tape reel, and the inventory of the collection. All four tapes are from the inaugural concerts by the Vienna Symphony with Carlo Maria Giulini; for program information, see Box 87.
      04-09-1974: Inside Auditorium Pickups
      [1974]: [2 tapes] Orchestra tune-up and rehearsal
      [1974]: "Egmont" Overture by L. van Beethoven
    - Video Tapes: Performances:, 1974; 4 open reel tapes (2" tape on 12 1/2" reel) (Box 89)
      04-09-1974: [4 tapes from the third night of the inaugural concerts, labeled with various camera numbers]
      Giulini, Carlo Maria; Wiener Symphoniker
    - Video Tapes: Performances:, 1974; 4 open reel tapes (2" tape on 12 1/2" reel) (Box 90)
      04-09-1974: Outside Auditorium Pickups
      04-09-1974: Auditorium Lobby Shots
      [04-07-1974?]: [2 tapes] Sunday Auditorium Rehearsal
    - Video Tapes: Performances:, 1974; 4 open reel tapes (2" tape on 12 1/2" reel) (Box 91)
      [1974]: Edited Master Emperor's Waltz by Strauss
      [1974]: Brahms Master
    - Video Tapes: Performances:, 1974; 3 open reel tapes (2" tape on 14" reel) (Box 92)
      04-09-1974: [3 tapes, labeled either "3rd Nite" or "Tuesday Night"]
    - Video Cassettes (Betacam SP, Hi8, U-matic, VHS): Performances and Miscellaneous:, 1989 -- 1994; video cassettes (Box 93)
      Contents of 33 Hi8 video cassette tapes are related to the Ivo Pogorelich International Piano Competition. The tapes are dated 11-30-1993 to 12-16-1993 and numbered sequentially from 1 to 33.
      Contents of 16 VHS video tapes, 1 U-matic tape and 1 Betacam SP tape are related to Sam Wanamaker, 1991 recipient of the Ambassador Award for Excellence, and his role in the reconstruction of Shakespeare's Globe Theatre in London.
      Globe Theatre (London, England: 1996- ); Ivo Pogorelich International Solo Piano Competition; Wanamaker, Sam
    - Film Reels: Performances and Miscellaneous:, 8 film reels (7 16mm and 1 35mm) (Box 608)
      One folder containing paper notes and other items removed from the original film containers and eight film reels wound on cores and stored in archival film cans, numbered and described as follows:
      [Folder:] (1) [items removed from film containers]
      [Film reels:] (1) 16mm film, [from printed label on original container:] “An Eastin School Film, Instruments of the Orchestra, Eastin Pictures Co., General Office, Davenport, Iowa”; (2) 16mm film, [from handwritten note inside original container:] “Arthur Rubinstein 16mm Film Possible magnetic audio signal Special projector needed to preview”; (3) 16mm film, [from handwritten note on original reel:] “Arthur Rubinstein Lecture at Recital Hall Magnetic audio signal Special projector is needed”; (4) 16mm film, [from handwritten note on original reel:] “Arthur Rubinstein 16mm Film Encores and Presentations January 15, 1975 No audio”; (5) 16mm film, [from label on original container:] “Ambassador College Audio-Visual Department, P.O. Box 111, Pasadena, California, U.S.A. 91109; Title: Ambassador Auditorium Worldwide Church of God Production, Print No. 15B, Footage: 1037, Time: 28’ 48”, color, sound,” [from separate label:] “Permafilm Protected Hollywood,” [from separate handwritten label:] “Not edited, slight scratching at HD - Film in good shape 3-8-82”; (6) 16mm film, [from handwritten note attached to original film container:] “16mm Film Arthur Rubinstein Lecture at Recital Hall [enclosed in a circle:] A”; (7) 35mm film, [from handwritten label on original container:] "Rubinstein Encores P 5118 Presentation 35/32 TRK,” [from handwritten note inside container:] “Optical audio signal 35mm format Needs special projector”; (8) 16mm film, [from handwritten label on original container:] “Rubinstein Encores, 5118 Pres. - 16mm Neg, PSP20 - 78 F.O.T. Spanish,” [from handwritten note inside container:] “Audio Signal of Recital Hall lecture Arthur Rubinstein”
      These eight film reels were originally located in three separate boxes and housed in various types of containers. Some reels show signs of deterioration (vinegar syndrome). The reels were wound onto archival cores and rehoused in plastic film cans at the Stanford Media Preservation Lab. The film cans were then consolidated in Box 608. The following is a complete description of the film reels and their original containers that was created before this preservation work took place:
      1. 16mm film reel in metal can with printed label: “An Eastin School Film, Instruments of the Orchestra, Eastin Pictures Co., General Office, Davenport, Iowa” [vinegar syndrome] (removed from Box 86)
      2. 16mm film reel in gray plastic can; handwritten note inside: “Arthur Rubinstein 16mm Film Possible magnetic audio signal Special projector needed to preview” (removed from Box 86)
      3. 16mm film on brown metal reel with handwritten note on reel: “Arthur Rubinstein Lecture at Recital Hall Magnetic audio signal Special projector is needed” (removed from Box 92)
      4. 16mm film on gray plastic reel with handwritten note on reel: “Arthur Rubinstein 16mm Film Encores and Presentations January 15, 1975 No audio” (removed from Box 92)
      5. 16mm film reel in brown metal can labeled: “Ambassador College Audio-Visual Department, P.O. Box 111, Pasadena, California, U.S.A. 91109; Title: Ambassador Auditorium Worldwide Church of God Production, Print No. 15B, Footage: 1037, Time: 28’ 48”, color, sound”; [separate label:] “Permafilm Protected Hollywood”; [separate handwritten label:] “Not edited, slight scratching at HD - Film in good shape 3-8-82” (removed from Box 92)
      6. 16mm film on plastic core inside padded mailing envelope in cardboard mailer; handwritten note attached to film: “16mm Film Arthur Rubinstein Lecture at Recital Hall [enclosed in a circle:] A” (in Box 608)
      7. 35mm film on plastic core in 11” x 11” square metal container; container labeled [handwritten]: Rubinstein Encores P 5118 Presentation 35/32 TRK”; handwritten note in box: “Optical audio signal 35mm format Needs special projector” [possible vinegar syndrome?] (in Box 608)
      8. 16mm film on metal reel in 11” x 11” square metal container; container labeled [handwritten]: “Rubinstein Encores, 5118 Pres. - 16mm Neg, PSP20 - 78 F.O.T. Spanish”; inside container, handwritten note on film reel: “Audio Signal of Recital Hall lecture Arthur Rubinstein” [vinegar syndrome] (in Box 608)
    - Video Tapes: Performances:, [01-15-1975]; 2 open reel tapes (1" tape on 9" reel) (Box 613)
      Two video tape reels labeled as follows:
      Rubinstein Performance Part 1 Length: 57 mins. 03-06-1991 Ambassador T.V. Prod. [NB: Rubinstein performed at the Ambassador on 01-15-1975]
      Rubinstein Performance Part 2 Length: 56:30 mins. 03-06-1991 Ambassador T.V. Prod.